







# **BIO**

FrontEnd Developer/Engineer with more than 6 years of experience and focused on Vue and React. I have been part of CORE teams performing tasks such as the development of a Design System, as well as the creation and governance of monorepos, CI/CD pipe implementations, documentation strategy. I also have a great deal of experience wrestling with APIS and do my best to keep up with the most important changes in the front-end ecosystem.

# **Working Experience**

**Frontend Software Engineer** 

# Sopra Steria

### 04/2022current

Job Title: Technical Lead Frontend

### Job Description:

- Planning and development of reverse logistics application for customer Leroy Merlin Spain.
- Technical validator of candidates
- Collaboration with the HR department in the development of training contents and technical talks
- Active participation in the company's FrontEnd community

Role: Team Lead & Developer

Tech Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue, CSS, SASS, Vite, Vitest, Cypress,

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

**Frontend Software Engineer** 

Atlax 360

# 10/2021 -04/2022

Job Title: FrontEnd Core Team

# **Job Description:**

- Development of a new architecture with the migration of the current Vue 2 to Vue 3, and a design system based on design-tokens and reusable and deliverable components for use with React, Vue and in its most native version using only css.
- Creation of addhoc tooling using Vite, ESBuild, among others
- Monorepo governance with Lerna and TurboRepo
- R&D tasks

Role: Team Lead & Developer

Tech Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue, React, CSS, SASS, Vite, ESBuild,

TurboRepo, Storybook, Testing-Library, Vitest, Cypress, Verdaccio

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

# Full-Stack JS developer

Sopra Steria	
06/2021 - 10/2021	Job Title: SPA's development proprietary at SOLUNION.  Role: Developer  Tech Stack: React, ES6, TypeScript, AWS, GraphQL, Jest, React-Testing-Library, Cypress, Gitlab  Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools
	TOTA Methodology. Agric, GOROM Framework, BIVA-GOM EDENGE 10013
03/2021 - 06/2021	Job Title: FrontEnd development proprietary at BBVA CIB  Role: Developer  Table Starts Desert Type Ceript Desert/Kulturgetee Jose Desert Testing Library
	<b>Tech Stack</b> : React, TypeScript, Docker/Kubernetes, Jest, React-Testing-Library, Cypress
	Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools
06/2020 - 03/2021	Job Title: BackEnd development proprietary at PagoFX.
	Role: Developer (Node)
	Tech Stack: Node, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, Jest, Joi, Docker/Kubernetes, GitLab
	Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools
09/2019 -	Job Title: SPA's development proprietary at SOLUNION.
06/2020	Role: Developer

Tech Stack: React, ES6, AWS, GraphQL, Jest, React-Testing-Library, Cypress,

Gitlab

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

# FrontEnd developer

# **HCL**

04/2019 -09/2019 Job Title: FrontEnd development proprietary at <a href="Mc">ING</a>.

Role: Developer

Tech Stack: ES5/6, BackBone JS, Jenkins, GitLab

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

# FrontEnd developer

## **Iteriam**

09/2018 -04/2019 Job Title: FrontEnd development proprietary at RSI

Role: Developer

Tech Stack: ES6, Vue2, Vuetify, Axios, Nuxt, GitLab

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

# FrontEnd developer

### **Malthus Darwin**

12/2016-09/2018 Job Title: FrontEnd development proprietary at Orange

Role: Developer

Tech Stack: AngularJS, Angular4, ES5/6, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

## FrontEnd developer

# Sipay - Smart Payment Solutions

08/2016 -11/2016 Job Title: FrontEnd development proprietary at Sipay

**Job Description:** 

Role: Web Designer / Developer

Tech Stack: ES5/6, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, VUE

Work methodology: Agile, SCRUM FrameWork, JIRA-CONFLUENCE tools

# **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

2016	JAVA Programming Master and ORACLE Data Base 12c.
2015	Web Design and Development with HTML5 and CSS3, Professional Course.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages	JavaScript (ES5, ES6), HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript
Frameworks & Enviroments	React, VueJS, Node
Cloud	AWS, Google Cloud
Tooling, CI-CD	GitLab, Jenkins, Artifactory, Docker-Kubernetes
Agile	Scrum – Jira & Confluence.